Привет и добро пожаловать в день 03 - День Указателей!
Указатели являются новым переменным типом, которому я собираюсь научить вас.
Это одна из самых полезных переменных в C.
Благоадря указателю вы сможете обладать адресом другой переменной
и удаленно изменять содержимое это переменной.
И это то, на что мы собираемся взглянуть в течение нескольких минут.
Для того, чтобы использовать указатели, вы должны в первую очередь понимать,
что то о Памяти.
Когда процесс запущен, у него есть право иметь практически всю существующую память.
С 32 битной системой мы будем обладать 4GB памяти, а с 64 битной системой, мы будем обладать гораздо большим количеством памяти.
Я не знаю наизусть точной цифры ... Но это 2 в 64 степени ...
Тут вам нужно использовать математику.
Так же нужно понимать что вся эта память для каждого процесса является виртуальной.
Which means than behind this memory, whether it's mapped somewhere on the RAM,
or on the hard drive, or wherever else... Do some research. And check out "swap",
and you might understand this better...
This memory is mapped by something called MMU,
which allows you to reserve memory somewhere, physically on the computer.
However, a given process has its own memory, and it does what it wants with it.
The memory is divided into two parts : high memory and low memory.
We call high memory, "stack". Dunno if you've hear this before, but ...
the stack... every time you call a function,
every time you do anything, etc... when you type "int a;" for example,
in your main, let's say... You've just allocated 4 bits, or 8,
depending on which architecture we're using, on the stack.
So on the high part of the memory.
So you're all the way at the top, at the level of 2 to the power of 64,
And little by little, you go down, along with the stack.
The more elements you add, the further down the stack you'll go.
On the other hand, you've got low memory. Also called "heap"
A notion we'll explore some other day.
The heap is the place where you can allocate memory.
Again, that's for another day.
In the next videos, we'll learn how pointers work and what they're for, etc...